Captioning Provided By:
MTV Networks
字幕提供者：
MTV网络
Are you ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Kids: Aye, aye, Captain.
孩子们：是的，是的，队长。
I can't  hear  you.
我听不到你说话。
Kids: Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：是啊是啊，队长！
Captain: ♪ Ohh... ♪
队长：♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
队长：♪ 吸水性的，黄色的
他是多孔的 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ If nautical nonsense
be somethin' you wish ♪
船长：♪ 如果是航海方面的废话
成为你所希望的那样 ♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
船长：♪ 然后降落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
Kids: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Ready? ♪
队长：♪ 准备好了吗？ ♪
All: ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
全部： ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ SpongeBob
SquarePants ♪
队长：♪ 海绵宝宝
方裤♪
SpongeBob and Patrick:
♪ ...Krabby Patty,
Krabby Patty, Krabby Patty ♪
海绵宝宝和帕特里克：
♪ ...螃蟹帕蒂，
蟹肉饼 蟹肉饼 ♪
♪ Squidward had a Krabby Patty
whose buns were white as snow ♪
♪ 章鱼哥吃了蟹肉饼
他的馒头白得像雪一样♪
Welcome to the Krusty Krab
欢迎来到蟹堡王
where it's almost as if
the evolutionary clock
ticks backward.
几乎就像
进化时钟
向后滴答作响。
♪ ...Squidward had
a Krabby Patty... ♪
♪ ...章鱼哥有
蟹肉饼...♪
Excuse me for just a second.
请原谅我一下。
♪ ...as snow ♪
♪ ...如雪 ♪
Do you mind, I'm trying to work
at a fast food restaurant.
你介意吗，我正在努力工作
在一家快餐店。
You might want to
try it some time!
你可能想要
尝试一下！
I sure would, Squidward,
that sounds-
我当然会的，章鱼哥，
听起来——
Hey, wait a minute.
嘿，等一下。
SpongeBob, you already  do
work at a fast food restaurant.
海绵宝宝，你已经这么做了
在一家快餐店工作。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
Yay!
耶！
Remind me to fire my therapist.
提醒我解雇我的治疗师。
And stop bringing
your neighbors to work.
并且停止携带
你的邻居去上班。
Patrick: We're not
just neighbors.
帕特里克：我们不是
只是邻居。
SpongeBob: You can
say that again.
海绵宝宝：你可以的
再说一遍。
Patrick: We're not just-
帕特里克：我们不只是——
Squidward: I don't care!
章鱼哥：我不在乎！
♪ Krabby Patty, Krabby Patty,
Krabby Patty... ♪
♪ 蟹黄派蒂，蟹黄派蒂，
蟹黄派蒂...♪
All right!
好的！
I am gonna- well, I don't know
what I'm gonna do, but-
我会——好吧，我不知道
我要做什么，但是-
♪ She'll be coming around the
Krabby Patty when she comes ♪
♪ 她会过来
蟹蟹帕蒂来了♪
SpongeBob, you nincompoop,
you broke my face.
海绵宝宝，你这个笨蛋，
你伤了我的脸。
Don't just stand there, help me.
别只是站在那儿，帮帮我吧。
I need a doctor.
我需要一名医生。
Woman: Doctor's office.
女：医生办公室。
Woman: You have a visitor
in the main lobby.
女：有客人来了
在主大堂。
Woman: Dr. Kravitz...
女人：克拉维茨博士……
SpongeBob: Oh, Doctor, is he
gonna be all right?
海绵宝宝：噢，博士，他是吗？
会没事的吗？
For the love of Neptune,
tell me.
为了海王星的爱，
告诉我。
Well, son-
好吧，儿子——
No, don't tell me!
不，别告诉我！
I can't take it.
我受不了。
We should know-
我们应该知道——
No, no, please,
just, just don't.
不，不，拜托，
只是，只是不要。
We won't know for two weeks,
you'll just have to wait.
两周后我们才知道
你只需要等待。
Two weeks, I'll never make it.
两周，我永远也到不了。
Mornin', SpongeBob,
you're early today.
早安，海绵宝宝，
你今天来早了。
Good morning, Nurse Wretched.
早上好，可怜的护士。
Hi, Mabel, saved the blue one
just for you.
嗨，梅布尔，救了蓝色的
只为你。
Oh, SpongeBob,
blue is my favorite color.
哦，海绵宝宝，
蓝色是我最喜欢的颜色。
Uh, or is it orange?
呃，还是橙色的？
I'll bet your amnesia's
gonna wear off in no time.
我敢打赌你有健忘症
很快就会消失。
My what?
我的什么？
Hi ya, Squidward.
嗨，章鱼哥。
I've been practicing
how to flop on my back.
我一直在练习
如何仰面翻倒。
We can't really
have you in here today.
我们真的不能
你今天在吗？
I'm going to be removing
Squidward's bandages
我要删除
章鱼哥的绷带
and he made me swear to
keep you far away from him.
他让我发誓
让你远离他。
It has been two weeks already?
已经两周了？
Don't worry, Doc, I promise
to stay out of the way.
别担心，医生，我保证
不碍事。
OK, as long as you stay
on the other side of the-
好吧，只要你留下来
在另一边-
Don't  rush  it.
别着急。
Sorry, go ahead.
抱歉，请继续。
SpongeBob: Wait!
海绵宝宝：等等！
Are you sure the patient has
enough  ?
你确定病人有
够了吗？
I have no idea what that is.
我不知道那是什么。
Please, just let me work.
请让我工作吧。
Very well, Doctor, carry on.
很好，博士，继续。
May I?
我可以？
Hold it, the readings on this
brain meter are all wrong,
we must postpone the operation.
坚持住，阅读这方面的内容
脑力计都错了
我们必须推迟手术。
That is a television set
put here for the
patients' enjoyment.
那是一台电视机
放在这里是为了
患者的享受。
And it's not even
plugged into the wall.
而且这还不是
插在墙上。
You're right, Doctor,
proceed with Operation: Sever.
你说得对，医生，
继续操作：切断。
SpongeBob: Hold it!
海绵宝宝：坚持住！
Woman: Doctor, we can't do this.
女：医生，我们不能这样做。
Surely we can use
a less-dangerous procedure.
当然我们可以使用
危险性较小的程序。
After all, we have to start
thinking about the welfare of-
毕竟我们必须开始
考虑以下人员的福利——
SpongeBob: Wait!
海绵宝宝：等等！
I just wanted to say sorry
for interrupting you before.
我只是想说声抱歉
因为之前打扰了你。
I, I...
我，我……
I can't believe it.
我简直不敢相信。
Squidward: SpongeBob?
章鱼哥：海绵宝宝？
Yeah?
是的？
Squidward: How does it look?
章鱼哥：看起来怎么样？
Great Neptune.
伟大的海王星。
Squidward: Come on,
spit it out, I can take it.
章鱼哥：来吧，
吐出来吧，我能接受。
Time for your medicine, mister-
mister... mister...
是时候该吃药了，先生——
先生……先生……
Handsome.
英俊的。
Ooh...
哦...
Squidward: What did she call me?
章鱼哥：她叫我什么？
Handsome, but she
spelled it wrong.
很帅，但是她
拼写错误。
Squidward: Quick,
hand me that mirror.
章鱼哥：快点，
把那面镜子递给我。
What the-
什么-
Wait a second...
等一下...
That nurse was right.
那位护士说得对。
I  am  handsome.
我很帅。
Eh, Squidward,
you're not handsome.
呃，章鱼哥，
你不帅。
You're a hunk!
你真是个猛男！
So handsome.
好帅啊
Handsome.
英俊的。
Hello, handsome.
你好，帅哥。
SpongeBob: Gee, Squidward,
people really seem to be
noticing how handsome
you are now.
海绵宝宝：哎呀，章鱼哥，
人们似乎真的是
注意到有多帅
你现在是。
You might even  more
handsome than before.
你甚至可能
比以前帅了。
Oh, so handsome.
哦，太帅了。
If that's even possible.
如果可能的话。
It's a miracle, I can walk.
我能走路了，真是个奇迹。
I can see.
我可以看到。
I can fly.
我能飞。
Uh-oh, my shoe's untied.
呃哦，我的鞋带解开了。
Mr. Handsome, can I
have your autograph?
帅哥先生可以吗
有你的签名吗？
No, not the book,
on my retainer.
不，不是书，
在我的保持器上。
Both: A limousine?
两人：一辆豪华轿车？
Well, SpongeBob, earlier today,
my spine was hurting.
好吧，海绵宝宝，今天早些时候，
我的脊椎很痛。
But now I'm resting on
fine, leather upholstery.
但现在我正在休息
精美的皮革内饰。
Well, I'm gonna go
clip my toenails, Squidward.
剪我的脚趾甲，章鱼哥。
Don't forget to
enjoy being handsome.
别忘了
享受帅气。
Oh, don't worry.
哦，别担心。
Handsome, handsome, handsome...
帅啊帅啊帅啊……
Gee, huh?
哎呀，是吗？
Well, better go
greet the commoners.
好吧，最好走
向平民问好。
Handsome, handsome, handsome...
帅啊帅啊帅啊……
Good morning, my people.
早上好，我的人民。
I'm sorry to have
kept you waiting, but
我很遗憾有
让你久等了，但是
even I,  ,
strange as it seems
连我也,,
看起来很奇怪
need my beauty sleep.
需要我的美容觉。
I want his shirt.
我想要他的衬衫。
I want his eyelids.
我想要他的眼皮。
I guess I kept them waiting
a little too long.
我想我让他们久等了
有点太长了。
I know.
我知道。
A little music should
soothe their hunger.
应该放一点音乐
缓解他们的饥饿。
Crowd: Handsome, handsome,
handsome, handsome...
人群：帅帅帅帅
帅哥，帅哥……
Hey, what is that sound?
嘿，那是什么声音？
Wait, it's him,
the handsome man!
等等，是他，
英俊的男人！
Beautiful  and  talented,
what more do they want?
美丽又才华横溢，
他们还想要什么？
Don't worry, folks, there's more
where that came from, and-
各位别担心，还有更多
那是从哪里来的，并且-
Hey!
嘿！
I got the clarinet.
我拿到了单簧管。
There's nothing a little
foaming, herbal bath can't cure.
没有一点什么
起泡沫，药草浴无法治愈。
Hey, my grandmother
gave me that soap.
嘿，我的祖母
给了我那块肥皂。
Well, no one ever said it'd be
easy being so handsome, Squiddy.
好吧，从来没有人说过它会是
鱿鱼，这么帅很容易。
You'll just have to start
getting used-
你只需要开始
习惯了-
Hi, handsome.
嗨，帅哥。
Handsome.
英俊的。
Augh.
啊啊。
Let's get him.
我们来抓住他吧。
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
You gotta help me.
你得帮助我。
They stole my bubble bath.
他们偷了我的泡泡浴。
Public life ain't all
it's cracked up to be.
公共生活不是全部
据推测是这样的。
I want my old life back.
我想要回到以前的生活。
Hmm, I know just what to do.
嗯，我知道该怎么做了。
Mr. Krabs: Squidward,
what have you done?
蟹老板：章鱼哥，
你做了什么？
You know what the Krusty Krab
means to me, don't you?
你知道蟹堡王是什么吗
对我来说意味着，不是吗？
And you took it upon yourself
to bring all these...
而你自己承担了这一切
把这些都带来...
these customers to me.
这些客户给我。
Hey, don't worry, folks.
嘿，别担心，伙计们。
There's plenty of Squidward
to go around
章鱼哥有很多
四处走走
so everybody just line up
and get your pocketbooks out.
所以大家就排队
拿出你的钱包。
For a small fee
of $14.98 per person
只需支付少量费用
每人 14.98 美元
everyone will get the
opportunity to touch Squidward.
每个人都会得到
有机会接触章鱼哥。
We don't have much time.
我们没有太多时间。
Take the door
and change me back.
拿门去
并把我变回来。
And I'll even throw in
a free soft drink
for an extra $3.
我什至会投入
一杯免费软饮料
额外支付 3 美元。
Come on, SpongeBob,
take the door and
smash my face back.
来吧，海绵宝宝，
开门并
打碎我的脸。
I can't.
我不能。
It was one thing
doing it by accident
这是一回事
无意中做的
but I can't hurt you on purpose.
但我不能故意伤害你。
You better hurt me,
or I'm really gonna hurt you!
你最好伤害我
不然我真的会伤害你！
Well, OK.
好吧，好吧。
Now don't hold back, SpongeBob,
just really let me have it.
现在别再犹豫了，海绵宝宝，
只是真的让我拥有它。
Just remember, Squidward.
请记住，章鱼哥。
This is going to hurt me more
than it's going to hurt you.
这会让我更加受伤
比它会伤害你。
Um, OK, let me just memorize-
嗯，好吧，让我记住一下——
Would you mind waiting till I-
你介意等我-
Hang on, you're starting to
look like your old self again.
坚持住，你开始了
再次看起来像以前的自己。
Nope, still too handsome.
不，还是太帅了。
It's still not working.
它仍然不起作用。
Maybe I'm not doing it
hard enough.
也许我没有这样做
够难的。
Squidward: Let me-
章鱼哥：让我——
Squidward, you're even
more handsome now.
章鱼哥，你还
现在更帅了。
And that crowd is in a frenzy.
那群人正陷入疯狂。
Well, SpongeBob, it was  you
who got me into this mess
嗯，海绵宝宝，就是你
谁让我陷入困境
now  you  have to
get me out again.
现在你必须
再次让我出去。
I know, Squidward.
我知道，章鱼哥。
, I'll think
of something.
,我会想
的某事。
, I just need,  ,
I just-
，我只需要，，
我只是——
Squidward, look out for
that falling shoe!
章鱼哥，小心
那只掉下来的鞋子！
Huh?
啊？
Squidward...
章鱼哥...
SpongeBob...
海绵宝宝...
You're back.
你回来了。
Oh, Squidward.
哦，章鱼哥。
I love you no matter how many
times we smash your face.
我爱你无论有多少
有时我们会打碎你的脸。
I almost wish
that meant something.
我几乎希望
这意味着什么。
Hey, where you going?
嘿，你要去哪里？
Don't leave me.
别离开我。
Please, I'm begging you.
拜托，我求求你了。
Look, I can make him
handsome again, watch.
瞧，我可以让他
又帅了，关注
See?
看？
He's getting handsome.
他越来越帅了
It just...
takes a little... effort.
它只是...
需要一点……努力。
Just a little... elbow grease.
只是一点点……肘部油脂。
Please... come back...
请……回来吧……
Neptune stirred up
quite a gale tonight.
海王星搅动了
今晚的风很大。
He must be mad about something.
他一定是因为什么事情生气了。
That's silly, everyone
knows Poseidon is ruler
of the undersea.
真是傻了大家
知道波塞冬是统治者
海底的。
Ah, my leftovers.
啊，我的剩菜。
: No...
： 不...
Why, dear Neptune?
为什么，亲爱的海王星？
Mm-hmm, goulash.
嗯嗯，炖牛肉。
Hey, out there,
you dropped your goulash.
嘿，在外面，
Hello...
你好...
My pores are whistling
in the wind.
我的毛孔在呼啸
在风中。
Aww, the little critter
likes my whistling pores.
哇哦，小动物
喜欢我呼啸的毛孔。
That tickles.
那很痒。
Deep Voice: Well...
低沉的声音：嗯……
My shift's over.
我的轮班结束了。
Time for work, SpongeBob.
工作时间到了，海绵宝宝。
All right, jelly, out you go.
好吧，果冻，你出去吧。
It's been real fun,
but I gotta get to work.
真的很有趣，
但我得去工作了。
Quite a wind this morning,
Eh, jelly?
今天早上风好大
呃，果冻？
Whoa...
哇...
Hey, Sparky, can you
tell your friends I don't
have time to play right now?
嘿，斯帕克，你可以吗？
告诉你的朋友我不
现在有时间玩吗？
Whoa...!
哇...！
I told you guys
I don't have time to play.
我告诉过你们
我没时间玩。
I have not been tardy one time
in my career as a fry cook.
我一次都没有迟到过
在我作为一名油炸厨师的职业生涯中。
And I'm not gonna start today.
我今天不会开始。
I need to call in some help.
我需要寻求帮助。
My fingers are too big
for the buttons.
我的手指太大了
对于按钮。
'ello, this be the Krusty Krab.
你好，这是蟹堡王。
Mr. Krabs, I need you.
蟹老板，我需要你。
SpongeBob, where you been?
海绵宝宝，你去哪儿了？
Customers are blowing in here
like nobody's business.
顾客纷至沓来
就像没人管的事一样。
I am sorry, Mr. Krabs,
but these jellyfish
don't want me to go to work.
对不起，蟹老板，
但这些水母
不想让我去上班。
Jellyfish?
海蜇？
They're attracted to my...
whistle-y holes.
他们被我的吸引...
口哨洞。
Uh...
呃...
I'll never understand
what you just said.
我永远不会明白
你刚才说的话。
But if it's transportation
you need, I know just the thing.
但如果是交通的话
你需要的，我就知道。
Got you.
明白你了。
Ooh, this one's
putting up a fight.
噢，这个是
打架。
Fightin' too hard.
打架太难了
You're gonna reel him in, Krabs,
you've gotta wear him down.
你要把他卷起来，蟹蟹，
你得让他疲惫不堪。
Give him a little slack.
给他一点松懈。
Yank.
猛拉。
A little slack...
有点松懈...
And yank.
并猛拉。
There he is, ready for work.
他就在那里，准备工作。
Draw back that point,
now get in there and start
pushing out them patties.
拉回那个点，
现在进入那里并开始
把它们推出来。
Aye-aye, sir.
是的，先生。
Let's get these Patties
started right.
让我们来吃这些肉饼吧
开始是对的。
Whoo.
呼。
That gives me an idea.
这给了我一个想法。
SpongeBob: Order up.
海绵宝宝：下单吧。
Ooh...
哦...
Ooh.
哦。
Oh, no, they found me.
哦，不，他们找到了我。
No, no-no, guys, please.
不，不，不，伙计们，拜托。
Uh, would you mind coming back
after business hours?
呃，你介意回来吗
下班后？
Heh, I'm trying to work here.
呵呵，我想在这里工作。
Reporter: The weather situation
is much worse across
the country.
记者：天气情况
更糟糕的是
国家。
And it doesn't look like
the winds are going to stop
anytime soon...
而且看起来并不像
风将会停止
很快...
Fishy go bye-bye.
鱼儿要再见了。
Ow.
噢。
And that's the way it is
in your world today.
事情就是这样
今天在你的世界里。
Boring.
无聊的。
I don't want to watch
any of this boring stuff.
我不想看
任何这些无聊的事情。
I want to watch
something decent, like-
我想看
一些像样的东西，比如——
SpongeBob: Sorry, Patrick,
I need a place to hide
from those jellyfish.
海绵宝宝：对不起，帕特里克，
我需要一个地方躲起来
来自那些水母。
What jellyfish?
什么水母？
Ever since the winds started
自从起风了
a sound whistles through
my holes that jellyfish
seem to love.
声音呼啸而过
我的水母洞
似乎很爱。
Hey, pal.
嘿，朋友。
SpongeBob, get out of here!
海绵宝宝，快离开这里！
I'm sorry, SpongeBob, but you've
become a negative influence.
对不起，海绵宝宝，但你已经
成为负面影响。
At least the wind stopped.
至少风停了。
I think I lost 'em.
我想我失去了他们。
Well, I guess I should just stay
in here, where it's safe.
好吧，我想我应该留下来
在这里，那里很安全。
And quiet.
而且安静。
And dark.
而且黑暗。
Oh...
哦...
It's OK, I'll only hide out here
for a second.
没关系，我就躲在这里
一会儿。
Yeah, it shouldn't take long.
是的，应该不会花很长时间。
Behind these rocks.
在这些岩石后面。
These sedentary, lifeless rocks.
这些静止的、没有生命的岩石。
Narrator: Later...
旁白：后来……
Hey, buddy, just thought
I'd spruce you up a little.
嘿，伙计，只是想
我会让你打扮得漂亮一点。
What's that?
那是什么？
Ooh, you don't say.
呵呵，你不说。
Well, guess what, you're my
best friend, too, mm-hmm.
好吧，你猜怎么着，你是我的
也是最好的朋友，嗯嗯。
Come on, let's have some fun.
来吧，让我们玩得开心吧。
Look, buddy, mm...
瞧，伙计，嗯……
Dinner's ready.
晚餐准备好了。
Here, let's have some tea.
来，我们喝点茶吧。
Want some sugar, buddy, huh?
哥们，要吃糖吗？
One lump or two?
一块还是两块？
Oh, you can have it all.
哦，你可以拥有这一切。
I feel comfortable around you.
在你身边我感觉很舒服。
Can I confess something,
'cause I know you'll understand.
我可以坦白一件事吗
因为我知道你会理解的。
I have this... problem.
我有这个...问题。
I seem to attract jellyfish.
我似乎吸引了水母。
Huh, how do you handle
a thing like that, hmm?
呵呵，你怎么处理
类似的事情，嗯？
Yeah, yeah, I'm at a loss, too.
是啊是啊，我也很失落。
Oh, barnacles!
哦，藤壶！
I'm gonna be
stuck in this cave forever!
我会是
永远被困在这个山洞里了！
Of course, buddy,
brilliant idea.
当然，哥们，
绝妙的主意。
We'll see what happens
this time.
我们看看会发生什么
这次。
Oh, here they come.
哦，他们来了。
Go get 'em, buddy.
去找他们吧，伙计。
What do you think of
my little friend's song?
你觉得怎么样
我小朋友的歌？
Something wrong?
有事吗？
Hmm, I created one stone
SpongeBob that uttered a note
in a foul key.
嗯，我创造了一颗石头
海绵宝宝发出了一张纸条
以犯规的方式。
But if I were to craft another
in a different size
但如果我要制作另一个
不同尺寸
the dimensions of
that hollow center
的尺寸
那个空心的中心
multiplied by
the number of holes
乘以
孔数
may offer another tune.
可能会提供另一种曲调。
One that could
soothe those jellyfish.
一个可以
安抚那些水母。
But which one is the right size?
但哪一种尺寸合适呢？
Eh, I guess I'll just
have to make a bunch of 'em.
呃，我想我只会
必须做一堆。
OK, that should do her.
好吧，那应该可以了。
Whoa, it actually worked.
哇，它确实有效。
I can go back to work now.
我现在可以回去工作了。
Krusty Krab, here I come.
蟹堡王我来了
How long was I gone?
我走了多久？
No...!
不...！
No...
不...
Narrator: 3,000 years later.
旁白：3000年后。
Woman: To this day, no one knows
why these mysterious statues
were created, or by whom.
女：至今无人知晓
为什么这些神秘的雕像
是被创造的，或者是由谁创造的。
All we know is
the genius of their design
我们所知道的是
他们的设计天才
has caused the annual migration
of jellyfish to their
wondrous tune.
引起了每年的迁徙
水母给他们的
美妙的曲调。
引起了每年的迁徙
水母给他们的
美妙的曲调。